

# **Jonathan Pierce**

UI/UX Designer & Front-End Developer

With a passion for efficiency, and effective design, my focus is helping design and development teams build and maintain thoughtful design systems. With a background in Adobe Experience Manager (AEM) and multi-brand organizations, my experience has taught me the value of scale; using atomic design principles and modern development methods to bridge the gap between design and development.

#### CONTACT

Ozark, MO 417-849-3965

piercedesign22@gmail.com

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science 2006 - 2010 Communication Studies Liberty University, Lynchburg, VA

## **APPS & SKILLS**

**Figma** 

Adobe XD

Sketch

**InVision** 

**Design Systems** 

**Atomic Design** 

**Adobe Creative Cloud** 

Adobe Experience Manager

**Responsive Design** 

**Application Design** 

iOS Design

Agile

**Google Analytics** 

JIRA/Confluence

Github

HTML5/Sass

**Zurb Foundation** 

**Bootstrap** 

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Nestle Purina North America 2020 - Current Senior UX Designer in St. Louis, MO (Remote)

This long-term contract position is centered around the design and development of a new design system for Purina's multi-brand website platform. Responsibilities include building atomic based design files (with Figma), collaboration with front-end developers, UX writing and documentation, workshops, training and workflows centered around ongoing maintenance. Also, responsible for designing the future state UI/UX of Purina.com.

Thinkful 2020 - Current

Student Mentor (Remote)

Support UI/UX students by acting as an advisor, counselor, and support system as they complete the course and land their first industry job.

## Bass Pro Shops 2019 - 2020

# Creative Manager (UI/UX Team) in Springfield, MO

Responsible for the leadership, direction, and mentorship of a team of designers, copywriters and front-end developers. This includes leading creative and holistic thinking across diverse product releases, platforms, and devices for White River Marine Group. Also responsible for delivering a UX vision, along with a plan for evolutionary, iterative updates, that actualize the larger vision over time.

## **TRAINING & AWARDS**

#### **AAF Gold Addy**

Tracker Off Road Website, 2020 Heartland

## **Apple App Store Feature**

Moxy, April 2015 Best New Apps and Lifestyle

Dapper, November 2014
Best New Apps, Lifestyle and Buy with
Apple Pay

#### **Reach Design Leadership Conference**

2017 New York, NY

#### **Adobe Summit**

2018 Las Vegas, NV

#### **Nielsen Norman Group**

UX Training 2019 Boston, MA
UX Training 2017 Chicago, IL
UX Training 2012 Chicago, IL

#### 2012 AMA Prism Award

Corporate Identity
Pickering Creative Group

# Bass Pro Shops 2015 - 2019

## Senior UI/UX Designer in Springfield, MO

Responsible for the UI/UX design for White River Marine Group; the parent company for marine brands like Tracker, Ranger, Nitro, Mako, Triton, Bass Pro Boating Center and more. This role's primary focus is centered around the migration to Adobe Experience Manager (AEM) for all brand websites. Aside from the UI/UX design, this includes creating and maintaining a central design system and component library, UX design for AEM internal authors and story writing for product requirements.

## Dapper Shopping, Inc. 2014 - 2015

## Lead UI/UX Designer in San Francisco, CA

Responsible for the overall UI/UX of the iOS app Dapper (for men) and Moxy (for women). Other roles include brand identity design, wireframing concepts, prototyping interactions, quality assurance and testing, design and HTML/CSS of the marketing website, design and HTML for transaction emails and marketing materials for web/print media.

## Liberty University 2012 - 2014

## Senior UI Designer in Lynchburg, VA

Design team lead for all web and app related projects. Responsible for creating and enforcing brand guidelines, prioritizing and assigning projects to designers and wireframing overall UX of each product. Projects included iOS and Android applications, responsive websites, complex internal web applications and student facing app tools.

# Pickering Creative Group 2010 - 2012

## Graphic Designer in Lynchburg, VA

Designed and developed ideas for various clients along the midwest and east coast. Included branding, web design, web development, print advertising, and marketing strategies.